Guide to the George A. Flagg papers, 1860-1883 and undated, bulk 1862-1866 RL.10051
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
George A. Flagg papers
1860-1883, bulk 1862-1866
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Flagg, George A.
RL.10051
9 Linear Feet
Captain George A. Flagg was the assistant quartermaster of the Army of the Potomac and was stationed at Harper's Ferry, West Virginia. The collection contains letters, reports, military telegrams, and papers pertaining to supplies and logistics in Maryland and West Virginia.
Biographical note
Captain George A. Flagg was the assistant quartermaster of the Army of the Potomac and was stationed at Harper's Ferry, West Virginia (1861-1866).
Collection Overview
The collection contains letters, reports, military telegrams, and papers pertaining to supplies and logistics in Maryland and West Virginia. Letters and telegrams include requisitions for supplies, recommendations, requests from civilians for payment or inquiries for the sale of goods, and letters concerning remuneration for property damage. There are also circulars dealing with quartermaster regulations, daily record sheets of supplies, account sheets of Flagg's activities, receipt rolls of hired men, and reports on the means of transportation and animals at Harpers Ferry.
Provenance
The George A. Flagg papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1952 and 1957.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Equipment and supplies; Quartermasters -- United States; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865 -- Claims; Harpers Ferry (W. Va.) -- History -- 19th century; United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865; United States. Army -- Supplies and stores; United States. Army -- Officers -- Correspondence; United States. Army -- Recruiting, enlistment, etc.; United States. Army -- Pay, allowances, etc.; United States. Army of the Potomac; Flagg, George A.
- George A. Flagg papers, 1860-1883 and undated, bulk 1862-1866; 1
  - Papers, 1860-1862 July; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers, 1862 Aug - 1863 Jan 19; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Papers, 1863 Jan. 20 April; 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Papers, 1863 May-1864 Feb.; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Papers, 1864 Mar.-Sept.; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - Papers, 1864 Oct. 1-Nov. 18; 3 folders (Box 6)
  - Letter copy book, 1864 Nov. 19-Dec.; 3 folders (Box 7)
  - Miscellaneous letters, 1865 Jan.-March; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1865 Apr.-June; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Journal, 1865 July-Dec.; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Papers, 1866 Jan.-1883; 4 folders (Box 11)
  - Bills, Receipts, and Reports, 1861-1865 Oct.; 3 folders (Box 12)
  - Bills, Receipts, and Reports, 1865 Nov.-1879 and undated; 2 folders (Box 13)